[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：现在看来我有一点经验
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Now it turns out I have a little bit of experience at
说服世界上的每个人去做正确的事情。
convincing everybody in the world to do the right thing.
&gt；&gt；观众：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：例如，
&gt;&gt; Audience: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: For example,
有JSON数据交换格式，
there's the JSON data interchange format,
世界上最受欢迎的数据交换格式。
the world's best loved data interchange format.
花了一段时间说服每个人，但最终每个人都同意了，而且
It took a while to convince everybody but eventually everybody got on board, and
死亡威胁停止了，我们现在都很高兴。
the death threat stopped and we're all happy about it now.
我很高兴地报告，这花费了不到一代人的时间。
I'm very happy to report that this took much less than a generation.
这是一种非常罕见的东西，我们可以在几分钟内移动它
This is one of those very rare things where we're able to move it in just a few
好几年了。
years.
因此，如果您查看Google Trends并比较JSON与XML的趋势，
So, if you look at Google Trends and compare the trends of JSON versus XML,
您将看到世界一直在对XML失去兴趣。
you'll see that the world has steadily been losing interest in XML.
看起来年份在这里被砍掉了，但它在另一个屏幕上。
Looks like that the years are chopped off here but it's on the other screen.
自2005年以来，世界一直对XML失去兴趣。
Since 2005 the world has steadily been losing interest in XML.
我们一直在慢慢地、悄悄地看到人们对JSON的兴趣在悄悄上升。
And we've slowly, quietly been seeing interest in JSON creeping up.
而这种增长并不是由任何行业推动的。
And this increase was not motivated by any industry.
没有JSON行业推动这一点，
There is no JSON industry which drives this there,
因为所有的工具都是免费和简单的，所以它之所以发生是因为
because all the tools are free and simple and so it's just happening because
你认为这是一种更好的做事方式，所以它只是采取了。
you decided this is a better way of doing things and so it's just taking up.
所以我不能预测这些线何时相交，但谷歌可以，所以看起来是下一个
So I can't predict when these lines cross over but Google can, so looks like next
当然，根据Google的说法，JSON在官方上比XML更有趣。
year for sure JSON becomes officially more interesting according to Google than XML.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：但是就使用JSON的用户而言，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: But in terms of use people who were using JSON,
作为数据交换，有更多的人使用JSON，对吗？
as a data interchange there's more people using JSON, right?
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我没有办法知道。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I have no way of knowing.
在我看来也是这样，但是-&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我认为他们只是
It seems like that to me too but- &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I think they're just
谷歌XML，因为它仍然是困难的，我们不必谷歌一个JSON，所以
Googling XML because it's still difficult and we don't have to Google a JSON so
经常是因为这很容易。
often cuz it's easy.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我认为那里有很多东西，是的，所以很多。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I think there's a lot to it there, yeah, so a lot of.
如果搜索建议，XML烂透了
If the search suggestions, XML sucks,
这是一件很流行的事情，你在JSON搜索中看不到这一点。
that's a popular thing, you don't see that on JSON searches.
因此，很可能会有这样的事情发生。
So there may very well be something to that.
因此，我并不打算让JSON成为最后一种数据交换格式。
So I did not intend for JSON to be the last data interchange format.
JSON旨在做一件非常具体的事情，允许用
JSON was intended to do a very specific thing of allowing applications written in
不同的语言能够通过
different languages to be able to communicate with each other over
互联网。
the Internet.
但是JSON现在被用于很多其他事情，
But JSON is now being used for lots of other things,
它并不一定是为它设计的，所以
things that it wasn't necessarily designed for and so
我预计它们也将是其他数据格式。
I expect they're going to be other data formats as well.
因此，我对任何可能正在设计另一种数据格式的人都有一些建议。
So, I have some advice to anybody else who might be designing another data format.
第一，请不要破坏JSON。
Number one, please don't break JSON.
JSON在它最初设计的目标上工作得非常好。
JSON is working really well for the thing that it was originally designed for.
我在JSON中做的最好的事情之一是，我没有在它上面放一个版本号。
One of the best things that I did in JSON was, I did not put a version number on it.
所以没有办法修改它。
So there is no way to revise it.
我们不能说JSON 1.1，因为没有JSON 1，它只是JSON。
We can't say JSON 1.1 because there was no JSON 1, it's just JSON.
所以它的方式，就是它永远的方式，
So the way it is, is the way it will always be,
这很好，因为如果你看一下堆栈。
which is great because if you look at the stack.
我预计随着时间的推移，每一层的堆叠都会不断变化，
I expect over the years the stack is gonna be changing all the time at every level,
除了JSON层。
except in the JSON layer.
JSON层将始终以现在的方式工作。
The JSON layer will always work the way it does right now.
这是一件非常好的事情，有那么高的可靠性，
And that's a pretty nice thing, having that level of reliability,
网络的完整性和任何东西都是巨大的。
the integrity and anything in the net is huge.
我想不出我们可以向JSON添加的任何功能比这更有价值。
I can't think of any feature we could add to JSON which is more valuable than that.
所以，如果你想做点别的，请做点别的
So, if you want to make something else, please make something else and
让它变得更好。
make it better.
但不要试图破坏JSON，不要管JSON。
But don't try to break JSON, leave JSON alone.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：无论你要做什么，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Whatever you're gonna do,
如果你要做一些类似于JSON但又不同的事情，
if you're gonna do something that's kind of like JSON but different,
让它变得更好。
make it significantly better.
如果只是JSON有一两个小东西，那么你所做的就是
If it's just JSON with one or two little things, then what you're doing is you're
给这个世界增加了兼容性风险，人们会
adding a compatibility hazard to the world, that people are gonna
必须处理类似于JSON但不是JSON的事情。
have to deal with this thing which is kind of like JSON but isn't.
所以这是要付出代价的。
And so there's a cost to that.
因此，确保成本是值得的，增加足够的价值，以证明该成本。
So make sure the cost is worth it, add enough value to it to justify that cost.
并获得一个更好的名称，因为毫无疑问，JSON最糟糕的地方就是名称。
And get a better name because no question, the worst thing about JSON is the name.
首先，人们对如何发音感到困惑。
For one thing people are confused about how to pronounce it.
我说JSON，很多人都说JSON，
I say JSON, a lot of people say JSON,
原来正确的发音是JSON。
it turns out the correct pronunciation is JSON.
&gt；&gt；观众：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：大家？
&gt;&gt; Audience: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Everybody?
&gt；&gt；观众：JSON。
&gt;&gt; Audience: JSON.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：[笑]是的，所以我一直听到一些叫Jason的家伙的来信
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: [LAUGH] Yeah, so and I hear from guys all the time named Jason
说，我在办公室，我听到有人说，什么。
saying, I'm in the office and I hear someone saying, what.
所以，如果你在这里，我很抱歉杰森。
So, I'm sorry Jason if you're here.
我不知道我在想什么，对不起。
I don't know what I was thinking, sorry.
所以我听说有个叫杰森的家伙威胁说
So I've heard from guys named Jason that threaten to make
新的标准叫做道格拉斯，所以只是为了向我展示它是什么样的。
new standards called Douglas, so just to show me what it's like.
但是，JSON最糟糕的地方还是名称。
But again, the worst thing about JSON is the name.
它代表JavaScript Object Notation，几乎所有关于它的东西都是错误的。
It stood for JavaScript Object Notation and almost everything about that is wrong.
所以我把它命名为JavaScript，因为我想表扬它
So I called it JavaScript because I wanted to give credit
到JavaScript，因为这就是这个想法的来源。
to JavaScript because that is where the idea came from.
JSON不是我发明的，我已经在这种语言中发现了它
I didn't invent JSON, I discovered it already in this language and
我只是想尊重它。
I was trying to give respect to it.
我并不是想跳到JavaScript的大衣尾巴上，因为我会在2001年告诉你，
I was not trying to jump on JavaScript's coat-tail because I'll tell you in 2001,
JavaScript不是一种非常受欢迎的语言，对吗？
JavaScript was not a much loved language, right?
说到这里，我是JavaScript，这不是一种从任何人那里获得信任的方式。
In saying, I'm JavaScript, that's not a way to get credibility from anybody.
我只是试着诚实，我只是试着认清它是从哪里来的。
I was just trying to be honest, I was just trying to recognize where it came from.
但是这个名字是有问题的，首先人们还不知道Java是什么
But the name is problematic, for one thing people still don't know what Java is
与JavaScript相比，这方面的工作仍在进行中。
versus JavaScript, and that stuff is still going on.
而且还有一个混淆，所以JSON只能与JavaScript一起工作，
And also there is a confusion that, so JSON only works with JavaScript,
不，那不是真的，从来都不是真的。
no, that's not true, that was never true.
还有一个令人困惑的地方，我猜JavaScript语言标准是
There is also a confusion that I guess the JavaScript language standard is
JSON的定义从来都不是真的。
what defines JSON and that was never true.
但所有这些困惑都是因为我选择了错误的名字。
But there are all these confusions that happened because I chose the wrong name.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：你应该怎么称呼它？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: What should you have called It?
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我不知道。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I don't know.
&gt；&gt；观众：[听不到]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：那艘船有
&gt;&gt; Audience: [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: That boat has
帆船，我们完事了。
sailed, we're done.
然后是物体，
Then there is object,
这里的Object表示JavaScript正确看待对象的方式，
object here represents the way that JavaScript thinks about objects right,
只是键值对的松散集合，这是一个对象。
just a loose collection of key value pairs, that's an object.
这不是大多数语言考虑对象的方式，对吗？
Which is not the way most languages think about objects, right?
他们有更脆弱的东西，我们有类和实例，等等。
They have this more brittle thing, we've got classes and instances, and so on.
所以他们会感到困惑，我们可以向他们发送JSON对象和
So they get confused that we can send them a JSON object and
他们去那不是一个物体，是的。
they go that's not an object, yeah.
符号，也许没问题。
Notation, maybe that's okay.
所以记法是不好的。
So notation is bad.
所以如果你要制定一个新的数据标准
So if you're going to make up a new data standard and
我认为你应该，不要叫它JSON。
I think you should, don't call it JSON.
不要在它前面贴一封信，或者
Don't stick a letter in front of it or
一封信或其他类似的东西。
a letter on the end of it or anything like that.
想出一些创意，在那里做点好事。
Come up with some creativity, do something good there.